Tom Nguyen

Los Angeles, CA 91732 • 858-249-9713 • huynguyen2412@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/huynguyen2412 • huytnguyen.com

Software Engineer Entry Level

Recent graduate with a degree in Management of Information Systems, and a minor in Computer Science, looking to leverage education and current studies with a position that utilized skills in the field of Computer Science and Software Engineering. Proven ability to integrate out-of-the-box thinking and problem solving analysis to improve processes, systems, and methodologies. Skilled at team collaboration while working independently in remote environments.

Areas of Expertise

- Software Design
- Database Design
- Development Process
- Agile/SCRUM

- Extensive Programming
- Operational Improvements
- User Requirements Gathering
- Web Development

- Ad-hoc Technical Support
- Network Troubleshooting
- Service and Quality Mindset
- Hardware Configuration

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems | San Diego State University, San Diego, CA, 12/2017

Minor – Computer Science

<u>Coursework</u>: Data Structure and Algorithms, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Data Management Systems, Info Systems Analysis and Design, Programming Language, Computer Architecture, Formal Language and Automata, Operating Systems

PROJECTS

Data Management Systems – Designed Database system for School of Pharmacy
Info System Analysis – Group project- Built Drone Delivery system for Pharmacy
Info System Design – Group Project – Designed and built Educational Game for low-income students
TECHNOLOGY PROFICIENCIES

Java, C#, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, ReactJS, NodeJS, Oracle PL/SQL, SQL Server, C++, Linux, Selenium IDE, Git

EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

FRAMEWORK SOLUTION, Santa Monica, CA 7/2018 to present

Software Developer Internship

Participate in retrospective reviews and work closely with the software development team to assist them in application design and testing. Learn how the software engineer team works with Product and Business to design and build the product features.

- Maintaining existing codebase, to including bug fixing and new feature development
- Create queries in T-SQL as stored procedures and function to eliminate manual development using SQL Server Studio.
- Testing, validate and fix the defects from the users' reports.
- Develop interface elements and components regarding to the customers' requirements.

HOOKIT, Solana Beach, CA 8/2017 to 12/2017

Data Coordinator Internship

Utilized articulate communications in conducting processing, analysis, interpretation, and maintained strong problem solving abilities to determine appropriate data types.

• Wrote data extraction queries and views for reporting utilizing SQL Server, and reported quality assurance and gained practical business experience.

SAN DIEGO STATE UNIVERSITY, San Diego, CA, 2015 to 1/2018

Computer Lab Assistant

Responsible for identifying, analyzing, and resolving technical problems in a professional manner by providing guidance to students and faculty on various software, tools, and applications such as Microsoft Word, Access, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, and Adobe. Conducted troubleshooting methods that resulted in a lab that was functioning and available for students.

 Assists with system security, installs proper security patching including anti-virus and anti-spam software. Diagnoses, repairs, and maintains various computer devices, network connections, and software. Test hardware to ensure security and develop key processes to enhance the instructional program. Helped and tutored students on math homework activities.